{
	"info": {
		"quizName": "Long Term Care Quiz",
		"creationDate": "3/19/2014",
		"creator": "Frank Bi",
		"url": "http://newshour.pbs.org",
		"shortUrl": "http://to.pbs.org/1dyu3sK",
		"twitterTextPart1": "I got ",
		"twitterTextPart2": "%25 on PBS @NewsHour's long term care quiz! Can you beat my score?"
	},
	"ques": [
		{
			"prompt":"What is the age of the youngest person known to have claimed long-term care insurance? ",
			"a":"34",
			"b":"56",
			"c":"68",
			"d":"76",
			"ans":"d",
			"blurb":"The youngest person to make a claim for long-term care insurance was 27 years old. The oldest was 103 years old, according to data from Genworth.",
			"img":""
		  },
		  {
			"prompt":"How many Americans have long-term care insurance?",
			"a":"5 million",
			"b":"1 million",
			"c":"8 million",
			"d":"20 million",
			"ans":"c",
			"blurb":"In 2012, 8.1 million Americans had long-term care insurance according to the American Association for Long-Term Care Insurance.",
			"img":""
		  },
		  {
			"prompt":"Which group's admissions to nursing homes have increased by 54% in the United States?",
			"a":"Hispanic",
			"b":"White",
			"c":"Hispanic and Asian",
			"d":"Asian",
			"ans":"c",
			"blurb":"Between 1999 and 2008, both Hispanic and Asian admissions to nursing homes increased by 54%, while white admissions decreased  10% and black admissions increased 11% according to the Administration on Aging at Brown University. ",
			"img":""
		  },
		  {
			"prompt":"What percent of individuals 44 and younger apply for long-term care insurance?",
			"a":"4%",
			"b":"10%",
			"c":"18%",
			"d":"25%",
			"ans":"a",
			"blurb":"Only 0.8% of people under 35 apply for long-term care insurance, while 3.2% of individuals between the age of 35-44 apply.",
			"img":""
		  },
		  {
			"prompt":"What costs more?",
			"a":"A year at Harvard",
			"b":"A year at a nursing home",
			"c":"A year in prison",
			"d":"A year of infant care in New York City",
			"ans":"b",
			"blurb":"Spending a year in a private room in a nursing home will set you back about $84,000 according to Genworth Financial. A year at Harvard is $56,000, an average year in prison is $31,000 and a year of infant care in New York City is around $14,000. ",
			"img":""
		  },
		  {
			"prompt":"Which state had the lowest unemployment rate for seniors in 2012?",
			"a":"North Dakota",
			"b":"Nevada",
			"c":"Massachusetts",
			"d":"Ohio",
			"ans":"a",
			"blurb":"North Dakota had an unemployment rate of 2.2%, while Nevada had the highest rate at 9.8%. Massachusetts came in at 6% and Ohio at 5.1%",
			"img":""
		  },
		  {
			"prompt":"Which state has the highest income tax rate on pensions?",
			"a":"Oregon",
			"b":"Minnesota",
			"c":"Virginia",
			"d":"Tennessee",
			"ans":"b",
			"blurb":"Minnesota has the highest pension tax rate, at 7.9%. Tennessee is one of nine states that has a 0% income tax rate. Oregon has 7.7% and Virginia has 5.3%.",
			"img":""
		  },
		  {
			"prompt":"Which state has the highest average retirement account balance? (not including pensions)",
			"a":"Vermont",
			"b":"New Jersey",
			"c":"Wisconsin",
			"d":"Connecticut",
			"ans":"c",
			"blurb":"Wisconsin has the highest average account balance at nearly $46,000, while Vermont has saved the least and averages just under $20,000. New Jersey has saved around $28,000 and Connecticut has saved an average of $24,000. ",
			"img":""
		  },
		  {
			"prompt":"How many Americans who need long-term care get help from family or friends?",
			"a":"1 in 6",
			"b":"2 in 3",
			"c":"1 in 100",
			"d":"9 in 10",
			"ans":"d",
			"blurb":"Nearly 9 in 10 Americans who need some form of long-term care get that assistance from family members or friends who volunteer their time. ",
			"img":""
		  },
		  {
			"prompt":"What is the value of all of that informal long-term care given by friends and family?",
			"a":"$100 million",
			"b":"$234 billion",
			"c":"$1.3 million",
			"d":"$2.5 billion",
			"ans":"b",
			"blurb":"In 2011 the Congressional Budget Office estimated the value provided by informal LTC caregivers doing home-aide type services was a whopping $234 billion. ",
			"img":""
		  },
		  {
			"prompt":"More than half of Americans underestimate the cost of what?",
			"a":"Assisted living facilities",
			"b":"Part-time aides",
			"c":"Most people have a good understanding of costs",
			"d":"Nursing homes",
			"ans":"d",
			"blurb":"58% of people underestimate the costs of a nursing home while 52% overestimate the cost of a part-time home healthcare aide. About a third of people either underestimate, correctly estimate and overestimate the cost of an assisted living facility according to an AP/NORC survey.",
			"img":""
		  }
	]
}
